<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-10-27T01:23:09-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Alex Ker</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">On Reading More</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/10/27/on-reading-more.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Reading More" /><published>2022-10-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/10/27/on-reading-more</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/10/27/on-reading-more.html">&lt;p&gt;layout: post
title: “On Reading More”
date: 2022-10-27 00:20:00 -0000
categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone intuitively knows the benefits of reading long-form in our low-attention and distracted economy dominated by TikToks and instant gratification. But where do you find motivation for getting through classics like Anna Karenina, or even the latest Sally Ronney novel that is supposedly entertaining? The answer lies in used book stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exhuming and reviving the would-be corpuses of books in clustered shelves under musty staircases is quintessential in the experience of used bookstores—this has developed into my frequent, comforting pastime. Bracketing the palpable joy in finding a used novel in near-mint condition that you’ve been on the hunt for the past six months and obvious environmental benefits, there’s more to browsing and procuring secondhand books compared to the one-click-buy option on Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Locating a book in the stacks of the library or an indie neighbourhood store takes time—the extensive acquisition process means you’re more likely to actually read what you get, as humans appreciate things that are harder to come by. Take advantage of this mechanic and avoid purposing books into sophisticated tabletop decor to impress guests, or a Zoom background that displays your apparent intellectual prowess (you deserve to do so only if you’ve read the book). Use the friction and organized chaos of used bookstores as a propellant to clear your reading list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time between you desiring a book and you getting a copy builds also wholesome anticipation. Release it by consuming that long-awaited story in one sitting, or in a 24 hour readathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exploitation and exploration strategy can also be readily applied in independent, local secondhand book shopping. In reinforcement learning, the exploitation means you take the optimal move according to a defined policy, while exploration means that you introduce a degree of randomness into learning to prevent yourself from being stuck in a local optimum. Balancing between exploitation and exploration is aligned with the nature of used bookstores. You might find what you came for, but you will accidentally see titles outside your preferred authors or genres, which is not the case in cleanly sectioned Barnes and Nobles. Used bookstores are curated by the tastes, aesthetics, and curiosities of the staff and local culture—the zeitgeist of the current epoch and of a bygone era—not simply the popular titles appealing to the masses. They reflect a kind of collective intellect of a group of people—maybe a group with mental frameworks you wish to emulate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you flipped through used books, apart from the forsaken efforts of highlighting and scribbly annotations in the margins, you might be able to collect feather bookmarks, read thoughtful notes addressed to friends and loved ones, or be confronted by a secret of the previous owner. Such human touches are the type of unpredictable hits of dopamine that add to your overall reading experience. Good luck finding unique memorabilia in novels distributed by Amazon warehouses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying and reading secondhand books is my current (healthy) addiction and form of procrastination. I’d take the surprises in the texture of an old book over the artificial smell of a new book any day. Try visiting to a used bookstore in your city—you might just become obsessed with its staff, books, and furry friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add me on Goodreads here: https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/115944140-alex-ker&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">layout: post title: “On Reading More” date: 2022-10-27 00:20:00 -0000 categories:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/10/26/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2022-10-26T22:44:37-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-26T22:44:37-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/10/26/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/10/26/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR&lt;/code&gt; is a four-digit number, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MONTH&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DAY&lt;/code&gt; are both two-digit numbers, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MARKUP&lt;/code&gt; is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;Tom&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &apos;Hi, Tom&apos; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry></feed>